When the lights go off the battle is on.
Night at the Museum: Battle of the Smithsonian is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Shawn Levy.
Hapless museum night watchman Larry Daley must help his living, breathing exhibit friends out of a
pickle now that they've been transferred to the archives at the Smithsonian Institution.
Larry's (mis)adventures this time include close encounters with
Amelia Earhart, Abe Lincoln and Ivan the Terrible.
Larry Daley, played by Ben Stiller.
Amelia Earhart, played by Amy Adams.
Jedediah Smith, played by Owen Wilson.
Kahmunrah / The Thinker / Abe Lincoln, played by Hank Azaria.
Theodore Roosevelt, played by Robin Williams.
Ivan the Terrible, played by Christopher Guest.
Night at the Museum: Battle of the Smithsonian is a 2009 American fantasy comedy film
directed by Shawn Levy, and written by Robert Ben Garant and Thomas Lennon.
The film stars Ben Stiller, Amy Adams, Owen Wilson, Hank Azaria,
Christopher Guest, Alain Chabat and Robin Williams.
It is the second film in the Night at the Museum series,
following Night at the Museum (2006).
The film was theatrically released on May 22, 2009, by 20th Century Fox.
It received mixed reviews and became a box-office success,
grossing $413 million on a $150 million budget.
A third film, Night at the Museum: Secret of the Tomb, was released in 2014, and an animated
sequel, Night at the Museum: Kahmunrah Rises Again, was released in 2022.
The film explores themes of museum, magical object,
duringcreditsstinger, pharaoh, amelia earhart.
The tone is lighthearted.